berlinale.de 2019-11-09

# Kulturveranstaltungen des Bundes in Berlin GmbH (KBB)

KBB GmbH (KBB) unites three institutions under one roof: The Berlin International Film Festival, the Berliner Festspiele with the Gropius Bau, and the Haus der Kulturen der Welt.  
KBB, Kulturveranstaltungen des Bundes in Berlin GmbH

In this document we inform you about our processing of your personal data and of your rights under data protection law. The specific data we collect and how we use them depends on the service offered. If you have any questions about this, please contact the specified contact persons.

## A. Who is responsible for the data processing, who is your contact person?

Body responsible for the data collection (“controller”):

Kulturveranstaltungen des Bundes in Berlin (KBB) GmbH  
Schöneberger Straße 15  
10963 Berlin, Germany  
Tel +49 30 26 397-0 (Head Office)  
Fax +49 30 26 397-397  

The KBB Data Protection Officer can be contacted at [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu)  
or our postal address with the addition “The Data Protection Officer”.

## B. Your rights

You have the following rights in your relationship with us with regard to the personal data relating to your person:

  * Right to information,
  * Right to correction or erasure,
  * Right to restrict processing,
  * Right to object to processing,
  * Right to data portability.

You also have the right to complain to a data protection supervisory authority about the processing of your personal data by us.

## C. Which personal data do we process? 

When you contact us by email, the data you submit to us (email, name where given) are stored in order to respond to your inquiry. The data collected in this context are deleted as soon as their storage is no longer necessary.

Which data we process in other contexts depends on the service used.

 **1\. Visit of our website, online journals or blogs**

If you merely visit our websites, online journals or blogs in order to inform yourself about the contents provided, we will only read the personal data which your browser transmits to our system. By that means, we process the data which are required to display our website and ensure stability and security. The processed data are: IP address, date and time of request, content of the requests (specific site), volume of data transferred, website sending the request, and browser ID.

The legal basis for the processing of these data is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

In addition to the aforementioned data, cookies are stored on your computer when you use our website. If you generally do not wish cookies to be used, please configure your browser accordingly. Detailed information about this can be found in Section F of this Privacy Policy. Please note that the use of some functions will in this case be restricted.

The legal basis for the use of cookies is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR.

For some of our applications, data are collected and stored for marketing and optimization purposes, using the technologies of etracker GmbH (https://www.etracker.com). This applies to the following websites: www.berlinale.de, www.efm-berlinale.de, www.berlinerfestspiele.de, www.hkw.de

User profiles may be created from these data under a pseudonym (site access, duration of visit, place of access, information about your terminal).

You can prevent the use of e-tracker by following the instructions in the links of the corresponding site and thereby activating the opt-out plug-in:

For other applications, we create pseudonymized user profiles from the same data (site access, duration of visit, place of access, information about your terminal) via the web analysis software Matomo. The data processing takes place on our own servers. This applies to the following applications: blog.berlinerfestspiele.de, theatertreffen-blog.de, www.berlinale-talents.de, www.epitext.hkw.de, www.anthropocene-curriculum, www.anthropocene-curriculum.org, journal.hkw.de, technosphere-magazine.hkw.de, blog.bundeswettbewerbe.berlin, www.projectfichte.org, b2b.berlinale.de, journeyofideasacross.hkw.de

You can prevent the use of Matomo by activating the “do not track” function in your browser, or unchecking the box below and thereby activating the opt-out plug-in: 

We use these technologies to enable us to analyze the use of and continually improve our website. We use cookies for this purpose. If you generally do not wish cookies to be used, please configure your browser accordingly. Detailed information about this can be found in Section F of this Privacy Policy. The legal basis for the use of e-tracker and Matomo and the setting of cookies is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR.

 **2\. Subscribing to our newsletters or customer mailings**

We are delighted that you wish to receive further information about our venues and programs or wish to receive our newsletters.

For a customer mailing or newsletter subscription (by email and/or post), you must register on our websites and give us your consent. We require the following personal data to send you our newsletter or register you for participation in customer mailings: Name, email address or postal address.

In order to subscribe to our newsletter or participate in customer mailings, we require your consent, which is the legal basis for processing your data according to Art. 6 (1) sentence 1 (a) GDPR.

To prove your consent to the sending of the newsletter or customer mailing, we use the so-called double opt-in procedure.

To be able to prove your consent, we use a so-called double-opt-in procedure. This means that following your registration for subscription we will send you an email to the email address provided in which you are asked to confirm that you wish to receive the newsletter.

If you do not confirm your subscription, your information will be deleted after expiry of the confirmation deadline stated in the email.

You may revoke your consent to the transmission of the newsletter and unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. You can declare revocation by clicking on the link provided in each newsletter email or by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu)

If you revoke your consent, you will no longer be sent any newsletters in future.

In connection with the sending of our newsletters, we forward your data to the email marketing service provider Newsletter2Go or campaign monitor, who work for us as contracted data processors and have contractually committed themselves to complying with the requirements of data protection law.

We use these technologies to enable us to design our newsletters in a more customer-friendly way and increase their attractiveness. We use cookies for this purpose. If you generally do not wish cookies to be used, please configure your browser accordingly. Detailed information about this can be found in Section F of this Privacy Policy.

The legal basis for the use of these technologies and the setting of cookies is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR.

Please note that the technologies of newsletter2go and campaign monitor analyze your user behavior. The data are collected strictly pseudonymously, i.e. the analysis is not combined with your other personal data, so that specific individuals cannot be identified.

newsletter2Go GmbH is domiciled in Nürnberger Straße 8, D-10787 Berlin, Germany. Information about data protection by the third-party provider is available at: <https://www.newsletter2go.de/datenschutz/> .

Campaign monitor is domiciled in Level 38, 201 Elizabeth Street, Sydney NSW 2000, Australia. Information about data protection by the third-party provider is available at: <https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/#privacy-policy> . Australia is outside the scope of application of the GDPR but is considered a country with an adequate standard of protection in terms of Art. 45 (9) GDPR.

In the case of a customer mailing or newsletter sent by post, we will forward your data to our service provider to prepare the shipment.

As a press representative, we continually inform you about our events in the context of public relations reporting. In this context, we store the following data: Name, email address, phone number, emphasis, medium and company. The legal basis for the processing of your data is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR. You may object to being sent this information at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

 **3 Our online shops**

If you wish to order tickets or merchandising products in our online shop, we store the following data, which are required to conclude the contract: Name, address, phone number, email address, date of birth, payment details, products ordered. The legal basis for this processing is the contractual relationship associated with the order according to Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR.

On the basis of the requirements of commercial law, we store your data for a period of ten years.

 **4 Applications on our website kbb.eu**

We are happy to receive your application. You can apply online on our website for advertised positions.

For this purpose, we use the online application tool from the company softgarden e-recruiting GmbH, Tauentzienstraße 14, 10789 Berlin, which processes your data for the purpose of conducting the application procedure on our behalf and in compliance with the legal requirements. We have obliged the company to ensure and comply with data protection with a contract for order processing. When you use the application tool, you leave our website and are taken to the supplier's website.

As part of the application process, all the personal data you enter is processed: name, date of birth, contact data such as address, email address, telephone number, data on training, school-leaving qualifications and/or a degree, certificates, details of other qualifications such as language skills, PC knowledge, application photos, information on desired salary and work samples.

The legal basis for the processing of your data is Art. 6 (1) clause (b) GDPR.

We use the personal data you enter exclusively for processing your application for the advertised position. If we sign an employment contract with you, your data will be stored for the purpose of processing the employment relationship and in compliance with the legal requirements.

If your application is unsuccessful, we hope that you will apply again to another position. We erase your data six months after you have been notified of the rejection.

 **5 Visiting and participating in our online forums and online portals**

With our online forums and online portals ("Kultur öffnet Welten", "Anthropozän Curriculum", "Synapse", "Expert*innen-Datenbank KIWit", etc., among others), we offer culture enthusiasts, creative artists, scientists and institutions a platform for cultural participation and exchange as part of projects. You have the ability to present yourself, your work or your initiative and to exchange ideas with others.

If you wish to obtain information on our platforms and/or to contribute to them, please fill out the relevant contact or registration form.

In this connection, we process the following personal data: name, institution, email address, telephone number, contact address, work specializations and details about your work or your institution.

If necessary, we pass on your data to our cooperation partners with which we operate the respective portal jointly and on a project-by-project basis. All our partners have been contractually obliged by us to comply with data protection regulations.

The legal basis for the processing of this data is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR. The disclosure of your data also takes place in the context of our contractual obligations. We store your data until you no longer wish to have your contributions published on our portal. If we do not include a contribution on our portals in individual cases, we will erase your data immediately. 

**6 Use of our apps**

Alongside our online services, we also offer a number of mobile apps, which you can download to your mobile device.

When a mobile app is downloaded, the required information is transmitted to the app store, i.e. user name, email address and customer number of your account, your device ID and the time of download. We have no influence over this data collection and are not responsible for the same. When we provide an app to you, we process the data specified under Point (1), “Our websites, online journals or blogs”.

The Berlinale App uses Google Analytics for mobile apps, a web analysis service which enables us to analyze the use of and continually improve our app. In this context, your IP address and information about your type of device are collected. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR.

You can prevent the collection of this information and its processing by objecting to its collection in the app settings (in “My Account” or “Info & Social”) via the check box “Activate Google Analytics”.

Details of the third-party provider: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001.

Information about data protection of the third-party provider: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html> , and the Privacy Policy: <http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy> . Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> .

Within the app, websites can be opened with your standard browser. Data collection in this case takes place in accordance with the standards of the respective website.

The app Arriving in Berlin uses the technology of Mapbox. Mapbox uses the collected data for internal analysis purposes in order to improve its own mapping products. Mapbox collects and stores the following data in this context: Start of session, map loading, map panning, map zoom, map tilt and swivel, temporary device location and time stamp, speed and course, visit, duration of visit and location. The location data collected are not interlinked with identifiable information such as name, permanent IDs, email addresses, IP addresses or phone numbers. We use Mapbox to enable you to navigate around the map. The legal basis for the use of Mapbox is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR.

You may object to the data collection by Mapbox at any time with effect for the future by setting an opt-out cookie, which is done by activating the deactivation function in the bottom left-hand corner of the map.

The application Mapbox, 85 2nd St Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, is an open-source project. Information about data protection by the third-party provider is available at <https://www.mapbox.com/privacy> . Mapbox has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> .

 **7 My program / My daily planner (Berlinale)**

To help you prepare for your visit to the Berlinale or the EFM (European Film Market), we offer you the service My program/My daily planner. In order to save your favorite program you will need to create an account. For this purpose, we save the following personal data via the function “My Account”: Name and email address. If you are interested in the Berlinale Generation program and are not at least 16 years of age, you will need to ask your parent or legal guardian to do this for you.

Once your account has been created you will be able to mark favorite programs. We will then save your chosen favorites. We do this on the basis of a contractual or pre-contractual relationship (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR).

We delete your favorite programs at the end of each festival season. We delete your account three years after its last use.

 **8 Accreditation and film registration for the Berlinale or the European Film Market (EFM).**

We are delighted that you wish to be accredited for the Berlinale or the EFM or wish to submit a film to the Berlinale.

In order to enable you to participate, we store the following personal data: Form of address, title(s), language of communication, name, address, company and position in the company, phone number, email address, website, date of birth, place of birth, length of stay, your payment details if applicable, your hotel in Berlin if applicable, nationality, country of origin, primary area of work, contribution to selected Berlinale film if applicable, portrait photograph and your professional identification (e.g. press pass).

If a film is submitted, we will also store the data related to the film and, if necessary, the film file itself. In addition, we will store your participation in Berlinale and EFM events.

We pass on these data to external service providers if this is necessary to fulfill our contractual relationship with you. If a film is submitted, we will pass your data on to the selection juries, whom we have obliged to observe to data protection. If you participate in the festival, the data will be forwarded in order to organize the festival security, your hotel accommodation, the Berlinale chauffeur service and the provision of your tickets. This concerns festival security, your hotel accommodation, the Berlinale transport service and the provision of your tickets. If you require a visa to enter the country, we will inform the Federal Foreign Office of the Federal Republic of Germany in order to support your visa application. This processing of your data is performed in order to fulfill our obligations arising in connection with your film submission or your accreditation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR).

In individual cases, we may need to pass on your data (name, place and date of birth) to the competent authorities for security reasons. The legal basis for the disclosure of the data is a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

At the same time, the Berlinale is one of the largest film festivals in the world and a meeting point of the international film scene. The EFM is one of the largest film fairs in the world. In order to safeguard our legitimate interests, we publish your data as participants and make them available to other members of the film industry who are involved in the festival. In the pursuit of the same interests, namely to promote networking in the international film scene, we forward your data to partners of the international film world in third-party countries, provided they guarantee the security of the data. Furthermore, we use your data to invite you to future festivals and inform you about our program. This processing of your data is performed on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

Due to their significance for the history of film, the data relating to your participation in the Berlinale or a submitted film will be stored permanently. In accordance with the provisions of commercial law, we store the data relating to your participation in the EFM for a period of ten years. If we reject your accreditation in individual cases, we will delete your data at the end of the festival season. Your place and date of birth, which we collect only for security reasons, will in any case be deleted at the end of the festival season.

 **9 Application to Berlinale Talents**

Berlinale Talents is a worldwide talent promotion platform for film and series creators. We’re delighted about your interest in us!

If you wish to submit an application you will first need to create an account. For this purpose, we save the following personal data: Name, address, email address, telephone number, date of birth, age, gender, nationality, country of origin, film projects and areas of work.

Once you have created your account, we would be delighted to receive your application. For this purpose, we store all additional information submitted by you: Social media account, company/university, portrait photograph, artistic work and career, educational path and the samples of your artistic work which you have provided.

We also pass on your data to the selection juries of our Talents Programs, who are contractually committed to us to comply with data protection. If you are selected for participation, we will also forward your data to external service providers. This concerns your hotel accommodation, the festival moderators, embassies and sponsors who provide financial support and enable your participation, and the provision of your tickets.

We process your data in order to fulfill our obligations arising from your participation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). The disclosure of your data to our service providers is likewise performed in the context of our contractual obligations.

If you wish to take part in a Talents Initiative of one of our partners worldwide rather than the Berlinale Talents in Berlin, we will make your data available to our partners.

In addition, we store your data in order to inform you about programs and worldwide Talents Initiatives in the future. We also publish your data in our publications and enable all former and current participants in the festival to access a selection of their data (name, country of origin, place of participation, sample of work) via our website. Berlinale Talents is a forum for film and series creators and providing this forum as a network to young artists is part of our mission to promote talent. This form of data processing and disclosure therefore takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to datenschutz@kbb.eu .

If you have been selected to participate in one of the Talents Initiatives, we will store your data permanently for archiving purposes.

If your application was unsuccessful, we regret this and hope that you will apply again. Five years after your last application, we will assume that you are no longer interested in our programs and will delete your data.

 **10 Submissions to the World Cinema Fund**

We are delighted that you submitted your project to the World Cinema Fund (WCF). For this purpose, we store all information submitted by you and the following personal data: Name, company, producer, director, scriptwriter, any other persons involved, samples of work and curricula vitae of producers and directors.

We pass on your data to the selection committees of our festival, who are contractually committed to us to comply with data protection. If you are invited to participate, we will forward your data to external service providers and partners. This will, if applicable, concern your accommodation and our cooperation partners, the German Federal Cultural Foundation (“Kulturstiftung des Bundes”) and the Federal Foreign Office. We store your data in order to fulfill our obligations arising from your participation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). The same applies to the disclosure of your data to the specified service providers and cooperation partners.

In addition, we store your data in order to inform you about programs and initiatives of the WCF in the future. We also publish your data in our publications. Our formats are a forum for film creators. This form of data processing and disclosure therefore takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

If your application for funding is successful, we will store your data permanently for archiving purposes.

If your application for funding is unsuccessful, we regret this and hope that you will submit further projects to the WCF in future. In this case, personal data will be deleted five years after submission.

 **11 Submissions to the Berlinale Co-Production Market**

We are delighted that you submitted your project to the Co-Production Market. For this purpose, we store all information submitted by you and the following personal data: Name, company, address, email, phone number, company profile, area of work, cast details and links to samples of work.

We pass on your data to our selection juries, who are contractually committed to us to comply with data protection. If you are selected for participation, we may also pass on your data to our cooperation partners Creative Europe MEDIA and MDM Mitteldeutsche Medienförderung. We store your data in order to fulfill our obligations arising from your participation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). The same applies to the disclosure of your data to the specified cooperation partners.

In addition, we store your data in order to inform you about our programs and initiatives in the future. We make your data available in the login area to other participants in the Co-Production Market and participants in the EFM to enable them to contact you. We may also disclose your data to public institutions for statistical or academic purposes. Our formats are a forum for internationally active producers and financiers and it is part of our mission, the promotion of promising young talent and of access to the market for European and international film creators, to provide participants with a forum. This form of data processing and disclosure therefore takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

The name, company address and contact data of the participants who consent to this in their application are disclosed to the online platform pro.festivalscope.com in order to activate your temporary free use of the platform, on which you can watch the previous films of directors of the selected projects. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (a) GDPR.

If your application for participation in the Co-Production Market is successful, your data will be stored permanently for archiving purposes.

If your application is unsuccessful, we regret this and hope that you will apply again. Five years after your last application, we will assume that you are no longer interested in our programs and will delete your data.

 **12 B2B site of the Berlinale**

B2B is a platform which we provide to future and current sponsors of the Berlinale. In order to enable future partners to enter into a collaboration this way, we collect the following personal data: Name, company and email address.

We store the following personal data about our current sponsors: Name of contact person, company and email address.

The data are provided to other sponsors of the Berlinale.

We store your data to meet our obligations arising from our partnership (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). At the same time, we wish to enable our sponsors to collaborate with other partners at the festival presentation. On the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR), we therefore pass on your data to other sponsors. You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to [datenschutz@kbb.eu](mailto:datenschutz@kbb.eu).

We delete these data at the end of the partnership or if there is no prospect of a future partnership.

 **13 Berlinale Contractor Portal**

On the Berlinale Contractor Portal (Berlinale-Dienstleister-Portal) our contractors register their suppliers and employees. The registration contributes to a smooth running of Berlinale.

In this context we process the following personal data: name of company, name of employee, role at Berlinale, date of birth, place of birth, maiden name, private address, portrait photo.

We process the data for the following purposes:

The processing of personal data serves to facilitate the provision of the contracted services, including the issuing of access passes as well as the granting of access rights to venues subject to specific security regulations.

The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) clause 1 (a) GDPR. We will delete this data 5 weeks after each Berlinale at the latest.

 **14 Application to the National Contests of the Berliner Festspiele**

We are delighted about your interest in our young talent festivals. If you wish to submit an application you will first need to create an account. For this purpose, we save the following personal data: Address, email address, phone number, age. Please note that accounts can only be opened by persons aged 16 or above. If you are below this age, please ask your parent or legal guardian to open an account for you, or apply by post, including their written consent. If you are below this age limit, we are only authorized to process your data if your parent or legal guardian has consented.

Once you have created your account, we would be delighted to receive your application. For this purpose, we store all information submitted by you: Name, address, date of birth, artistic work and career, type of education and the samples of your artistic work which you have provided.

We pass on your data to the selection juries of our festivals, who are contractually committed to us to comply with the requirements of data protection law.

If you are selected for participation, we will also forward your data to external service providers. This concerns your hotel accommodation and the provision of your tickets.

We store your data in order to fulfill our obligations arising from your participation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). The disclosure of your data to our service providers is likewise performed in the context of our contractual obligations.

In addition, we store your data in order to inform you about the programs and initiatives of our talent promotion scheme in the future. We also publish them in our publications and on our website. Our young talent programs are a forum for young artists, and it is part of our mission, the promotion of young talent, to provide young artists with this forum. This form of data processing therefore takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR). You may object to this form of processing and the disclosure at any time by sending an email to datenschutz@kbb.eu .

If you have been selected for our young talent programs, we will store your data permanently for archiving purposes.

If your application was unsuccessful, we regret this and hope that you will apply again. Five years after your last application, we will assume that you are no longer interested in our programs and will delete your data. However, you may also at any time delete your account and accordingly all your data yourself.

 **15 Open Calls and Workshops (Call for participation in artistic and scientific programms and workshops)**

We welcome your application to our open calls and workshops for different artistic und scientific programms. For this purpose we store all information you provide to us, including your personal data.

We disclose your personal data to our selection panel. The members of the selection panel are representatives of our cooperation partners. These have been contractually bound to comply with the applicable data privacy regulations. We store your personal data in order to comply with our obligations resulting from your participation (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (b) GDPR). This also applies to the disclosure of your data to our national and international cooperation partners, who have been contractually bound to comply with the applicable data privacy regulations.

Additionally we use your data to inform you about our programs and initiatives in the future. This processing and disclosure of your data is based on a balancing of interests (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR). You can object to this processing and disclosure of your personal data at any time by e-mailing us at datenschutz@kbb.eu .

If your application is successful, we will permanently store your personal data for record purposes. If your application is not successful, we regret this and we will delete your personal data after the end of the application period.

## D. Additionally used technologies

The following service providers provide services on our websites. These may include video and audio files, direction maps or web fonts.

When you access the corresponding site, your browser will download the contents directly from the third-party provider. This lets the third-party provider know which of our websites you are visiting. As the web service provider, we have no knowledge about the data collected by the third-party provider. Please consult the websites of the providers for information about the terms of use and the privacy policies. If you have a user account with the third-party provider, the provider may link this information to your account. Third-party providers may use cookies. If you generally do not wish cookies to be used, please configure your browser accordingly. Detailed information about this can be found in Section F of this Privacy Policy. The use of these technologies takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR).

 **1\. Third-party providers**

 _Google Maps_

We use Google Maps on the websites www.berlinale.de, www.efm-berlinale.de, www.berlinerfestspiele.de, www.hkw.de, www.kultur-oeffnet-welten.de and www.kbb.eu, in order to display the location and directions to our venues and other places of interest to you.  
Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA  
Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, [www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) . 

_Google Webfonts_

 _Ooyala_

We use Ooyala on the website www.berlinale.de to display videos.  
Ooyala, Inc. Attn: Privacy, 800 W El Camino Real, Suite 350, Mountain View, CA, 94040 <http://www.ooyala.com/privacy>   
To protect your data, we have agreed standard data protection clauses with Ooyala in accordance with the directives of the EU Commission.

 _Youtube_

We use Youtube on the websites www.berlinerfestspiele.de, blog.berlinerfestspiele.de, theatertreffen-blog.de, www.epitext.hkw.de, www.anthropocene-curriculum.org, journal.hkw.de, technosphere-magazine.hkw.de, blog.bundeswettbewerbe.berlin, www.projectfichte.org and www.berlinale-talents.de to display Videos.  
YouTube LLC, 01 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA  
Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, [www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) . 

_Vimeo_

 _SoundCloud_

We use SoundCloud on the websites www.hkw.de, blog.berlinerfestspiele.de, theatertreffen-blog.de, www.epitext.hkw.de, www.anthropocene-curriculum.org, journal.hkw.de, technosphere-magazine.hkw.de, blog.bundeswettbewerbe.berlin, www.projectfichte.org and www.berlinerfestspiele.de to play audio files.  
SoundCloud Ltd., Legal Team, Rheinsberger Str. 76/77, 10115 Berlin   

_Spotify_

We use Spotify on the website www.hkw.de to play audio files.  
Spotify AB, Regeringsgatan 19, SE-111 53 Stockholm, Schweden  
<https://www.spotify.com/de/privacy/>

_Twitter_

We use Twitter on the websites www.hkw.de, blog.berlinerfestspiele.de, theatertreffen-blog.de, www.epitext.hkw.de, www.anthropocene-curriculum.org, journal.hkw.de, technosphere-magazine.hkw.de, blog.bundeswettbewerbe.berlin, www.projectfichte.org and www.berlinerfestspiele.de to display and link to the messages of our venues on the Twitter network.  
Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street Dublin 2, D02 AX07 Ireland  
Twitter has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, [www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) . 

_JW Player_

We use JW Player on the websites www.hkw.de www.berlinale.de and www.berlinerfestspiele.de JW Player to display audio and video contents.  
LongTail Ad Solutions Inc., 8 West 38th Street, 6th Floor, New York, NY 10018, USA  
JW Player has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, [www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) . 

_TOP-IX_

We use TOP-IX on the website www.berlinale.de and in the Berlinale app to display videos and enable live broadcasting of events.  
CONSORZIO TOP-IX, via Maria Vittoria 38 – 10123 Torino, Italien  

_1000° Epaper_

We use the 1000° Epaper solution on the websites www.hkw.de, www.berlinale.de and www.berlinerfestspiele.de to display a number of publications of our venues.   
Mark Busse, Mozartstr. 3, 04107 Leipzig  

_The Hoefler Type Foundry_

We use solutions of Hoefler & Co. on the website www.berlinale-talents.de to display fonts  
The Hoefler Type Foundry, Inc. d/b/a Hoefler & Co., 611 Broadway, Room 725 New York, NY 10012-2608 USA  
The Hoefler Type Foundry hat sich dem EU-US Privacy Shield unterworfen, [www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) . 

_Flowplayer_

We use solutions of Flowplayer AB on the websitewww.berlinale-talents.de to display videos  
Flowplayer AB, Mäster Samuelsgatan 36, 11157, STOCKHOLM, SWEDEN  

_Serve-u_

We use solutions of serve-u on the website www.berlinale-talents.de to display live streams and videos.  
serve-u technical support Buchholz & Sünderhauf GbR, Kamminer Str. 7, 10589 Berlin  

## E. Retargeting technology 

On the website of the Berliner Festspiele, we use the retargeting technology of the service providers Google and Adition. You may object to personalized advertising on our website https://www.berlinerfestspiele.de or by sending an email to datenschutz@kbb.de.

The use of these technologies takes place on the basis of a weighing of interests (Art. 6 (1) clause 1 (f) GDPR).

The third-party providers specified herein insert advertisements on websites on the internet and for this purpose use stored cookies on the basis of users’ previous visits to the website of Berliner Festspiele.

 **1 Google Doubleclick**

Doubleclick by Google ( www.doubleclick.com ) uses technologies to display advertisements which are suitable for you. The provider of Doubleclick is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Mountain View, Barrow St Dublin 4, Ireland. If you do not wish any further anonymized data to be collected by Doubleclick, please click https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb#display_optout (“OptOut”). This OptOut cookie deletes the previously stored information and prevents any further collection of information. If you have already activated the “OptOut” you may at any time reverse this setting by clicking the “OptIn” button.

 **2 Google Remarketing**

The website www.berlinerfestspiele.de also uses the Google program for interest-based advertising, so-called Google Remarketing. You may also deactivate the use of cookies by Google for these purposes by accessing the deactivation site for Google advertising ( <https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html> ). Alternatively, users may deactivate the use of cookies by third parties by visiting the deactivation page of the Network Advertising Initiative ( <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> ) 

Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework.

 **3 Adition**

Adition ( [https://www.adition.com](https://www.adition.com/) ) uses technologies to present you with advertising which is relevant to you. The provider of Adition is Adition technologies AG, Am Gatherhof 44, 40472 Düsseldorf, Germany. If you do not wish any further anonymized data to be collected by Adition, you can deactivate data collection here ( <https://www.adition.com/privacy/> ). This OptOut cookie deletes the previously stored information and prevents any further collection of information. If you have already activated the “OptOut” you may at any time reverse this setting by clicking the “OptIn” button.

## F Technical notes

Cookies are data packages which are exchanged between your browser and the website. They serve the purpose of storing information across several website visits, for example to allocate shopping carts or implement a website registration. They enable identifications to be transferred securely in your network. Your browser stores the cookies on your computer. Cookies cannot execute applications and are not viruses. 

Some functions of the website require the transfer of cookies as a technical basis. If you deactivate cookies, you will no longer be able to use these functions.

Where third-party providers are involved, these may also use cookies. This allows third-party providers to track your internet usage across several websites. The transfer of cookies to third-party providers can be reviewed in your browser settings. The loading of third-party provider contents can be managed through extensions, such as “NoScript”, “AdBlock” or “uBlock Origin”.

Version of: September 2019
